<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Device>
    <Name>ADXL345</Name>
    <Description>
         The ADXL345 is a small, thin, ultralow power, 3-axis accelerometer with high
         resolution (13-bit) measurement at up to +/-16 g. Digital output data is
         formatted as 16-bit twos complement and is acces-sible through either a SPI (3-
         or 4-wire) or I2C digital interface.  
         
         The ADXL345 is well suited for mobile device applications. It measures the
         static acceleration of gravity in tilt-sensing appli-cations, as well as
         dynamic acceleration resulting from motion or shock. Its high resolution (3.9 m
         g /LSB) enables measurement of inclination changes less than 1.0 degree. 
         
         Several special sensing functions are provided. Activity and inactivity sensing
         detect the presence or lack of motion by comparing the acceleration on any axis
         with user-set thresholds. 
         
         Tap sensing detects single and double taps in any direction. Free-fall sensing
         detects if the device is falling. These functions can be mapped individually to
         either of two interrupt output pins.  An integrated, patent pending memory
         management system with a 32-level first in, first out (FIFO) buffer can be used
         to store data to minimize host processor activity and lower overall system
         power consumption.  
         
         Low power modes enable intelligent motion-based power management with threshold
         sensing and active acceleration measurement at extremely low power dissipation. 

    </Description>
    <Manufacturer>ADI</Manufacturer>

    <Category>Sensor</Category>
    <SubCategory>Accelerometer</SubCategory>

    <KeyWord>
         Accelerometer, ADXL345, 3-Axis, I2C, SPI, Pulse detect, Quick motion detection, Click
    </KeyWord>

    <Communication>
        <Interface>I2C</Interface>
        <Interface>SPI</Interface>
    </Communication>

    <WebPage>
        http://www.analog.com/en/mems-sensors/mems-inertial-sensors/adxl345/products/product.html
    </WebPage>

    <Datasheet>
        http://www.analog.com/static/imported-files/data_sheets/ADXL345.pdf
    </Datasheet>

    <Doc>$Device_ROOT$\doc\</Doc>

</Device>
