<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Device>
    <Name>LIS302DL</Name>
    <Description>
        The LIS302DL is an ultra compact low-power three axes linear accelerometer.
        It includes a sensing element and an IC interface able to provide the measured acceleration
        to the external world through I2C/SPI serial interface. 
        The sensing element, capable of detecting the acceleration, is manufactured using a dedicated
        process developed by ST to produce inertial sensors and actuators in silicon.
        The IC interface is manufactured using a CMOS process that allows to design a dedicated circuit
        which is trimmed to better match the sensing element characteristics. 
        The LIS302DL has dynamically user selectable full scales of +-2g/+-8g and it is capable of
        measuring accelerations with an output data rate of 100 Hz or 400 Hz.
        A self-test capability allows the user to check the functioning of the sensor in the final application. 
        The device may be configured to generate inertial wake-up/free-fall interrupt signals when a
        programmable acceleration threshold is crossed at least in one of the three axes.
        Thresholds and timing of interrupt generators are programmable by the end user on the fly.
    </Description>
    <Manufacturer>ST</Manufacturer>

    <Category>Sensor</Category>
    <SubCategory>Accelerometer</SubCategory>

    <KeyWord>ST, Accelerometer, LIS302DL, 3-Axis, I2C, SPI, FreeFall, Click</KeyWord>

    <Communication>
        <Interface>I2C</Interface>
        <Interface>SPI</Interface>
    </Communication>

    <WebPage>
        http://www.st.com/internet/analog/product/152913.jsp
    </WebPage>

    <Datasheet>
        http://www.st.com/internet/com/TECHNICAL_RESOURCES/TECHNICAL_LITERATURE/DATASHEET/CD00135460.pdf
    </Datasheet>

    <APPLICATION_NOTES>
        AN2579: LIS302DL 3-axis digital MEMS accelerometer translates finger taps into actions
        http://www.st.com/internet/com/TECHNICAL_RESOURCES/TECHNICAL_LITERATURE/APPLICATION_NOTE/CD00163557.pdf

        AN2335: LIS302DL: 3-Axis - +-2g/+-8g digital output ultracompact linear accelerometer
        http://www.st.com/internet/com/TECHNICAL_RESOURCES/TECHNICAL_LITERATURE/APPLICATION_NOTE/CD00098549.pdf
    </APPLICATION_NOTES>

    <Doc>$Device_ROOT$\doc\</Doc>

</Device>
